<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding on Chris Meserole</title>
    <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding on Chris Meserole</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2004-2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chrismeserole.com/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Edarf</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/installing-edarf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/installing-edarf/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to check out random forests in general and the edarf package in particular for a while now &amp;ndash; at least since Zach Jones and Fridolin Linder posted their paper on Random Forests and EDA last spring.
I finally had a chance to go through package, and it&amp;rsquo;s as great as I&amp;rsquo;d hoped it would be. The standard errors and partial dependence plots point toward a future where ML plays a much larger role in political science overall rather than just the subset devoted to prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poisson Saturated Log Likelihood</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/poisson-saturated-log-likelihood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/poisson-saturated-log-likelihood/</guid>
      <description>I was poking around the web earlier for the saturated log-likehood in a poisson model, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it.
Here goes, using an example from Millar&amp;rsquo;s MLE Estimation and Inference:
library(MASS) z &amp;lt;- c(rep(0,19), 1,1,2,2,3,3,3,3,4,4,4,5,6,6,6,6,7,7,7,9,9) mod &amp;lt;- glm(z~1,family=&amp;quot;poisson&amp;quot;) z.pos &amp;lt;- z[(z&amp;gt;0)] saturated.ll &amp;lt;- sum(z.pos*log(z.pos)-z.pos-log(factorial((z.pos)))) intercept.ll &amp;lt;- as.numeric(logLik(mod)) saturated.ll intercept.ll (my.null.deviance &amp;lt;- 2*(saturated.ll-intercept.ll)) mod$null.deviance  If it&amp;rsquo;s easier to understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on, also try this:
total &amp;lt;- 0 for(i in 1:40){ if(z[i]&amp;gt;0) total &amp;lt;- total + z[i]*log(z[i])-(z[i])-log(factorial(z[i])) else # can&#39;t evaluate log(0) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example R and Python Code</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/example-r-and-python-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/example-r-and-python-code/</guid>
      <description>In addition to Python, Lark now executes R at runtime as well, via Knitr.
Still have an issue with Maplotlib, but otherwise things are looking good!
Here goes. First let&amp;rsquo;s try R:
x &amp;lt;- rnorm(100) summary(x)  Now let&amp;rsquo;s switch over to Python:
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x = 3 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x + 1 [should be 4] &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 2 + 2*x missing or wrong results will be overwritten  Ok. Let&amp;rsquo;s try plotting stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lark Now Runs Python</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/lark-now-runs-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/lark-now-runs-python/</guid>
      <description>One reason I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing Lark, the static site generator that now powers this site, was to have the freedom to cook up unique ways of merging writing and data analysis.
Thankfully, I&amp;rsquo;m glad to say I hit the first milestone on that path today. It took a bit of hacking, but thanks to Matthew Rocklin&amp;rsquo;s great new pymarkdown module, Lark now executes Python code blocks in posts when it builds the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rd2pdf bug in devtools::check()</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/rd2pdf-bug-in-devtoolscheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/rd2pdf-bug-in-devtoolscheck/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently trying to compile my first package in RStudio.
I was consistently getting the following warning:
* checking PDF version of manual ... WARNING LaTeX errors when creating PDF version.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a clue what was going on, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t having any success following Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s advice to check my LaTeX logs; I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know where the logs were.
Thankfully though, a bit of google discovered the problem: as Matt Bannert noted in R 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Valgrind on Mac OS X Yosemite</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/installing-valgrind-on-mac-os-x-yosemite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/installing-valgrind-on-mac-os-x-yosemite/</guid>
      <description>I decided to learn a lower level like like C, in part because I want to learn about memory management, leaks, etc.
While following Zed Shaw&amp;rsquo;s tutorial I got stuck on installing Valgrind, which isn&amp;rsquo;t yet supported on Yosemite.
To get up and running, I generally followed Taras Kalapun&amp;rsquo;s tutorial, which installs Valgrind from svn. However, initially I ran into issues because aclocal and autoconf weren&amp;rsquo;t installed. Then I ran into issues because XCode wasn&amp;rsquo;t installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Octave Graphics on Mac OS X 10.8.4</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/loading-octave-graphics-on-mac-os-x-10.8.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/loading-octave-graphics-on-mac-os-x-10.8.4/</guid>
      <description>I decided to try my hand at Octave today, to see if it simplifies model prototyping.
One issue was that Octave wasn&amp;rsquo;t connecting properly to its graphics library. Anytime I ran hist(), for example, I would get:
dyld: Library not loaded: /usr/X11/lib/libfreetype.6.dylib Referenced from: /usr/X11R6/lib/libfontconfig.1.dylib Reason: Incompatible library version: libfontconfig.1.dylib requires version 13.0.0 or later, but libfreetype.6.dylib provides version 10.0.0 dyld: Library not loaded: /usr/X11/lib/libfreetype.6.dylib Referenced from: /usr/X11R6/lib/libfontconfig.1.dylib Reason: Incompatible library version: libfontconfig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Ruby Versions</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/managing-ruby-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/managing-ruby-versions/</guid>
      <description>For a project I&amp;rsquo;m working on, I needed to install the command line interface for AWS Elastic MapReduce.
The catch is that the CLI requires using ruby 1.8.7, and is not compatible with later versions. Bummer, because when I ran ruby -v I learned I was using 1.9.3.
However, I had a vague memory of upgrading to 1.9.3 when I was either playing with Rails or installing Jekyll a couple months back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pushing Jekyll to s3</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/pushing-jekyll-to-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/pushing-jekyll-to-s3/</guid>
      <description>I have two workstations. The first is a custom built desktop that runs Windows (more on this later, hopefully). The second is an Asus laptop that primarily runs Linux.
I recently moved my sites over to Jekyll. I host them locally in a Dropbox directory, then push them to s3.
On Windows, I use jekyll-s3 to do the push. It&amp;rsquo;s convenient and works well. Just run gem install jekyll-s3 and then to push you run jekyll-s3 (the first time you do this, it walks you through configuration).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Jekyll on Windows</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/installing-jekyll-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/installing-jekyll-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>There are two ways to install jekyll: the easy way and the (relatively) hard way.
####THE EASY WAY
The easy way is to download Railsinstaller. It sets up ruby, rails, bundler and other packages in C:\Railsinstaller. (Note: since I already have git installed elsewhere, I unchecked the install dialog box for git and ssh.)
Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got Railsinstaller up and running, open powershell and run:
cd C:/Railsinstaller gem install jekyll  I tried to run gem install rdiscount as well, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Jekyll Set-Up</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/my-jekyll-set-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/my-jekyll-set-up/</guid>
      <description>I was pretty frustrated with how slowly this site was running, so I recently followed the herd and moved over to Jekyll.
The transition was pretty smooth, but there were two issues I encountered.
Redirecting the Index I wanted the homepage for chrismeserole.com to forward to my /about/ page. In wordpress, this is pretty trivial &amp;ndash; I think it was just a check box in the settings tab.
But for Jekyll it&amp;rsquo;s not so simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Octoprress</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/install-octoprress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/install-octoprress/</guid>
      <description>Install Octopress
I followed this tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Workflow with Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/git-workflow-with-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/git-workflow-with-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Early in 2013 I switched over to using Jekyll for this site and a couple others.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the workflow I use to edit one of the sites. First, I open terminal or Powershell and start a new branch:
cd ~Dropbox/Sites/mysite git checkout -b draft  Then I edit relevant files and commit the changes:
git commit -a -m &#39;Edited such-and-such file&#39;  Or I&amp;rsquo;ll add a file and commit the change:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Install Checklist</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/linux-install-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/linux-install-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Last Updated: Feb 16, 2013.
Just installed Ubuntu 12.10 for the first time, on my Asus UL30VT from an external DVD.
The following is a checklist I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting together for how to set up a Linux install.
####Get Spotify Working
First, open /etc/apt/sources.list. This will open a dialog box asking for a repository. Type this:
deb http://repository.spotify.com stable non-free  Then, open terminal and run:
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install spotify-client  That should do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and Github Notes</title>
      <link>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/git-and-github-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrismeserole.com/coding/git-and-github-notes/</guid>
      <description>These are just notes of my experience with git and github. If you know of better/best practices, by all means let me know.
Initially I had trouble running fetch or push to my github repository. Every time I ran fetch, for instance, I got:
fatal: The remote end hung up unexpectedly  The reason I was getting this &amp;ndash; I think &amp;ndash; is that I ran
git remote add origin git://github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>